owlgen.com 2016-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Owlgen

**Owlgen  Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we actually collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information for our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website or blog??**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address or other details to help you with your experience. You can also login through your facebook,google+ and twitter account.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you register on our site or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards.  
We only provide articles and information. We also use regular Malware Scanning.

We do not use an SSL certificate  
• We do not need an SSL because:  
We are not making any transactions and we are only showing free information.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**  
• **Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.  
• Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third-party services that track this information on our behalf.**

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable the cookies, some features will be disabled. But, just don’t worry as it won’t affect the user’s experience.

However, you can still place orders .

**Third-party disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.

**Third-party links**

We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website.

Google

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

We have not enabled Google AdSense on our site yet but we may do so in the future.

> California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is a first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:  
Users can visit our site anonymously.  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:  
• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Users are able to change their personal information:  
• By logging in to their account

How does our site handle do not track signals?  
We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?  
It’s also important to note that we do not allow third-party behavioral tracking

> COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
We will notify the users via email  
• Within 7 business days  
We will notify the users via in-site notification  
• Within 7 business days

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**Content By The User**

Content means any information, text, graphics, or other materials uploaded, downloaded or appearing on the Service. You as in the User retain ownership of all Content that you submit, post, display, or otherwise make available on the Service.

**Your License to Owlgen**  
By submitting, posting or displaying Content on or through the Service, you actually grant us a worldwide, non-exclusive, royalty-free license (with the right to sublicense) to completely use, copy, reproduce, process, adapt, modify, publish, transmit, display and distribute such Content in any and all media or distribution methods (now known or later developed).

You as a user agree that this license includes all the right for other users of the Service to modify your Content, and for Owlgen to make all of your Content available to others for the publication, distribution, syndication, or broadcast of such Content on other media and services, subject to our terms and conditions for such Content use. Such additional uses by Owlgen or others may be made with no compensation paid to you with respect to the Content that you submit, post, transmit or otherwise make available through the Service.

You grant us the permission to modify or adapt the Content you posted in order to transmit, display or distribute it over various networks and in various media and/or make changes to your Content as are necessary to conform and adapt that Content to any requirements or limitations of any networks, devices, services or media.

You also represent, warrant and agree that you have not and will not contribute any Content that

(i) violates or otherwise interferes with any copyright or trademark of another party,

(ii) reveals any trade or other secrets that should not be disclosed, unless the secret belongs to you or you have the owner’s complete permission to disclose it,

(iii) create an impression that you know is incorrect, misleading, or deceptive, including by impersonating others or otherwise misrepresenting your affiliation with a person or entity;

(iv) contains other people’s private or personally identifiable information without their express authorization and permission, and/or

(v) contains or links to a virus, trojan horse, worm, time bomb or other computer programming routine or engine that is intended to damage, detrimentally interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system, data or information. Owlgen reserves the right in its discretion to remove any Content from the Site, suspend or terminate your account at any time, or pursue any other remedy or relief available under equity or law.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to:

To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at info@owlgen.com  
and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.  
**

**Contacting Us:-**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

www.owlgen.com  
info@owlgen.com
